Welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So, in our last video, we
talked on societies in the Americas
before Europeans came in contact. Well,
Mr. Christopher Columbus arrives onto
America in 1492, and that changes the
way of history for the Americas forever.
Essentially, the various European
countries decided that they were going
to explore and conquest this new land.
The reasons for this are very simple.
It's the three G's: gold, God, and
glory. First, Europeans want to gain
more wealth, which was at the time
measured in gold and silver under a
system called mercantilism. Since there
was a lot of gold in the Americas,
conquering land allowed for mines to
open up and more wealth going to
European countries. The second reason
was that Europeans saw the native
civilizations in the New World and felt
a kind of religious obligation to spread
and convert the natives to Christianity
with a special effort from Jesuit
missionaries. Finally, there was glory.
Back then, the more land a country
controlled, the more powerful it was
considered. The Americas offered a new
frontier to claim and show off to the
rest of the world, and that's pretty
much it. On the screen now are AP-style
questions you should be able to answer
for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
See you in the next one.